<resources>
    <string name="app_name">green_grow</string>
    <string name="article_1">As part of its efforts to promote agricultural development in the country and to strengthen its partnerships with various industry players, the Department of Agriculture (DA) once again joins forces with international exhibition organizer Informa Markets in bringing the Livestock and Aquaculture Philippines 2024.\n\n
This year marks the seventh installment of the said exposition. With an annual average of at least 250 exhibitors and 10,000 visitors from over 30 countries, the Livestock and Aquaculture Philippines steadily gained fame as the Philippines’ premier event for the livestock, poultry, meat, and animal feeds industries.\n\n
The Office of the Undersecretary for Livestock and the National Livestock Program (NLP) leads the Department’s preparations for the three-day expo.\n\n
Sharing his experiences during his visit to the Livestock Vietnam as well as the renewed partnership with Informa Markets, DA Undersecretary for Livestock Deogracias Victor Savellano conveyed his thoughts on how the Livestock and Aquaculture Philippines can open a wide variety of opportunities for its participants, most especially the Filipino livestock and poultry raisers.\n\n
“Ang maganda po rito ay we will be showcasing different technologies, we will have participants and companies from different countries, and we will also be having meetings with our ASEAN partners,” expressed Usec. Savellano.\n\n
Aligned with the expo’s theme, “Harnessing Innovation and Technology for Sustainable Farm Development,” DA-NLP Director Dr. Jonathan Sabiniano signified that the Department aims to disseminate information on the role of technologies and innovations in the development of the Philippine livestock and poultry industries and to share applied research and technology transfers with livestock and poultry raisers during the three-day event.\n\n
He added that the Livestock and Aquaculture Philippines is the perfect platform for exchanging ideas, breakthroughs, best practices, and updates in livestock and poultry farming as well as for forging and strengthening partnerships between the government, the private sector, and other partners in the international arena.\n\n
“There are several changes in the environment right now. Aside from the changing climate, there are also changes in the landscape. The agricultural areas are now shrinking, we have less space now for livestock raising, and decreasing soil fertility wherein forages and feeds of our livestock and poultry animals are also affected. So in this expo, we are going to find ways and solutions to these uncontrollable problems and hopefully we can also introduce technologies and innovations that would solve these problems,” shared Dir. Sabiniano.
This year’s Livestock and Aquaculture Philippines will happen from May 22 to 24, 2024 at the World Trade Center (WTC) Metro Manila, Pasay City.\n\n
“The event is quite similar every year but this year, we will be focusing more on innovations and other things that the Philippines is looking at like biosecurity. I’m really looking forward to bringing this event to the farmers from all over the Philippines and also supporting them so that they can visit the show, attend the conferences and seminars, and learn from the show,” said Rungphech Chitanuwat, Country General Manager of Informa Markets in the Philippines.\n\n
Nine DA units—the NLP, the Bureau of Animal Industry (BAI), the National Meat Inspection Service (NMIS), the National Dairy Authority (NDA), the Philippine Carabao Center (PCC), the International Training Center on Pig Husbandry (ITCPH), the Agricultural Training Institute (ATI), the Bureau of Agriculture and Fisheries Standards (BAFS), and the Philippine Council for Agriculture and Fisheries (PCAF)—as well as the government financial institution Land Bank of the Philippines will comprise the DA Pavilion.\n\n
The DA Pavilion will showcase the diverse initiatives of the agriculture department and will cater to the inquiries, concerns, and suggestions of the expo attendees. Experts from several DA units will also share their expertise on livestock-, poultry-, feeds-, and aquaculture-related topics during technical seminars and conferences throughout the three-day event.\n\n
Meanwhile, the expo’s sub-event Livestock Philippines Recognition 2024 will take place on May 22, where select companies, institutions, organizations, cooperatives, and individuals will be acknowledged for their significant role in pursuing excellence in their respective fields towards the development of the livestock and poultry industries in the Philippines. ### (Krystelle Ymari A. Vergara, DA-AFID)\n\n</string>

    <string name="article_2">President Ferdinand Marcos, Jr.’s administration’s initiatives to modernize agriculture and support farmers and fishermen contributed to the growth of the farm and fishery sector in the first quarter, despite challenges posed by El Niño and increased input costs.\n\n
The value of production in agriculture and fisheries, based on constant 2018 prices, rose in the January-March quarter by 0.05 percent to P428.99 billion due mainly on the strong performance of the poultry subsector.\n\n
Data from the Philippine Statistics Authority showed that the value of poultry production rose by 5.9 percent in the first quarter to P68.76 billion, helping balance the contraction in value of crops, fish, and livestock produced during the quarter. The increases were seen in the production of chicken, chicken eggs, and ducks.\n\n
“Interventions and assistance provided by the government allowed the agriculture sector to fare better this time compared to periods in the past when we had El Niño,” said Agriculture Secretary Francisco P. Tiu Laurel, Jr.\n\n
“The impact of reduced rainfall and hotter temperatures were evident in lower crops and fisheries production in the first quarter. If El Nino will persist through the second quarter, we’re cautiously optimistic that the interventions we have taken will allow the agriculture sector to mend and return better results between April and June,” he addedn
Despite the 0.3 percent decrease in crop production, which represented nearly 57.6 percent or P247.04 billion of total agricultural output, and a 1.3 percent decline in fisheries production to PhP 53.73 billion, corn production increased by 0.5 percent during the quarter.\n\n
Farming and fishery provide millions of jobs for Filipinos and is the centerpiece of the government’s program to ensure the country’s food security and keep inflation in check.\n\n</string>

    <string name="article_3">The Department of Agriculture (DA)—through the Office of the Undersecretary for Livestock, the National Livestock Program (NLP), and the Bureau of Fisheries and Aquatic Resources (BFAR)—collaborates anew with private events organizer Informa Markets in showcasing the status, trends, issues, and opportunities in the Philippine livestock, poultry, and fisheries subsectors at the Livestock and Aquaculture Philippines 2024.\n\n
Now on its seventh installment, this year’s Livestock and Aquaculture Philippines gives prominence to modern and sustainable agriculture with the theme, “Harnessing Innovation and Technology for Sustainable Farm Development.”\n\n
An estimated 280 exhibitors from over 30 countries are expected to feature their products, technologies, and innovations to participating farmers and fisherfolk, veterinarians, animal nutritionists, meat processors, feed manufacturers and millers, veterinary drugs and products manufacturers, integrators, importers, traders, members of the academe, national and foreign dignitaries, and other agricultural stakeholders.\n\n
The DA Pavilion will highlight the programs and services of the NLP, Bureau of Animal Industry (BAI), National Meat Inspection Service (NMIS), National Dairy Authority (NDA), Philippine Carabao Center (PCC), International Training Center on Pig Husbandry (ITCPH), Agricultural Training Institute (ATI), Bureau of Agriculture and Fisheries Standards (BAFS), Philippine Council for Agriculture and Fisheries (PCAF), and the government financial institution Land Bank of the Philippines. The DA-BFAR will also demonstrate its various initiatives for local fisheries, hatcheries, aquaculture, and mariculture at the Aquaculture Pavilion.\n\n
Experts from various DA units are set to conduct lectures during conferences, technical seminars, and fora throughout the three-day expo.\n\n
The Livestock and Aquaculture Philippines 2024 will run from May 22 to 24 at the World Trade Center Metro Manila, Pasay City.\n\n
The first day of the expo will also honor companies, institutions, organizations, cooperatives, and individuals who have significantly contributed to the development of the local livestock, poultry, and aquaculture subsectors with the conduct of the second Livestock Philippines Recognition. ### (Krystelle Ymari A. Vergara, DA-AFID)\n\n</string>

    <string name="article_4">The Department of Agriculture (DA) vows to implement proactive and effective zoonotic disease prevention and control as it assumes chairmanship of the Philippine Inter-agency Committee on Zoonoses (PhilCZ) during the ceremonial turnover of chairmanship from the Department of Health (DOH) to the DA for the years 2024 to 2025.\n\n
“This transition underscores the importance of strong collaboration in our efforts to combat zoonotic diseases, echoing the principle of the One Health approach. Under the provisional guidance of PhilCZ, we are committed to ensuring a nation that is responsive in detecting, preventing, educating, and eliminating zoonotic diseases, thereby promoting the health and wellbeing of both the animal and human population,” emphasized DA Undersecretary for Livestock, Deogracias Victor Savellano, during the turnover ceremony held at Salvador H. Escudero III Hall, National Meat Inspection Service, on May 6, 2024.\n\n
In 2011, Presidential Administrative Order (AO) No. 10 established the PhilCZ, comprising the DA, DOH, and DENR, along with their respective agencies as members.\n\n
PhilCZ aims to formulate a national strategy and implement efficient mechanisms to prevent, control, and eradicate diseases transmissible between animals and humans such as Avian Influenza, Rabies, and Leptospirosis, among other infections.\n\n
Dr. Constante Palabrica, DA Assistant Secretary for Swine and Poultry and OIC director of the Bureau of Animal Industry, said that cases of zoonotic diseases such as Avian Influenza (AI) and rabies are still continuously reported in the country.\n\n
“When it comes to rabies, in 2023, halos isang Pinoy ang namamatay kada araw dahil sa rabies, ngayong 2024, tuloy-tuloy pa rin ang cases ng rabies. Sa Avian Influenza, well-monitored naman ito ng Department, merong mga probinsya pa na may kaso ng AI tulad ng Pampanga, Nueva Ecija, Tarlac, Laguna, Kalinga, Cagayan, Bataan,” he stressed.\n\n
Despite some provinces having AI cases, Asec. Palabrica added that ten provinces in the country were declared free of the disease, including Camarines Sur, Davao del Sur, Rizal, South Cotabato, Ilocos Sur, Batangas, Capiz, Quezon, Aurora, and Ilocos Norte.\n\n
He assured that the DA is vigilant in monitoring AI and other zoonotic diseases through its Bureau of Animal Industry.\n\n
Joining the turnover ceremony were DOH Undersecretary Dr. Glenn Mathew Baggao; Director of DOH Epidemiology Bureau Dr. Alethea De Guzman; DENR Assistant Secretary for International Affairs and concurrent OIC-Director of the Biodiversity Management Bureau Marcial Amaro, Jr., together with officials and representatives from the Bureau of Animal Industry, National Meat Inspection Service, Food and Agriculture Organization, and United States Agency for International Development. ### (Ira Y. Cruz, DA-AFID)\n\n</string>

    <string name="article_5">The Department of Agriculture, on May 6, urged Congress to restore the National Food Authority’s function as a rice price stabilizer and increase its fund allocation for programs to enhance rice production and farmers’ incomes as lawmakers’ deliberate on measures seeking to extend the Rice Tariffication Law.\n\n
In his report to the House of Representatives’ Committee on Agriculture chaired by Quezon Rep. Wilfrido Mark Enverga, DA Secretary Francisco P. Tiu Laurel, Jr. lauded the RTL as a landmark legislation that provided “the platform and infrastructure to increase the productivity and incomes of farmers even as competition arising from freer importation stands to benefit consumers.”\n\n
Since the law’s passage in 2019,  especially with lawmakers’ inclusion of the provision that created Rice Competitiveness Enhancement Fund, the agri chief said hundreds of thousands of farmers have benefited from financial assistance, better seeds, technical services and training as well as farm machinery and equipment that were granted under the Rice Fund.\n\n
“We recognize that much needs to be done to ensure that we attain the best possible outcome vis-a-vis identified targets under RTL given the remaining time we have before the law expires,” said Secretary Tiu Laurel.\n\n
The role of rice, not just in food security but in determining economic policy, cannot be overstated at this time when global prices of the commodity had risen because of tightness in supply and worries over production due to El Niño.\n\n
The DA chief said changes to the RTL is needed in view of climate change that shortened the frequency of El Niño events to 3-5 years.\n\n
Given the lack of significant investments in agricultural infrastructures over the past 27 years, the DA supports the extension of RTL and the increase of Rice Fund allocated to enhance farmers’ productivity and competitiveness through greater mechanization, wider use of better technology and inputs including seeds and fertilizers, and an expanded network of postharvest facilities like dryers, mills, silos and warehouses.\n\n
“Mr. Chairman and members of the committee, the continuation of the RTL is the way to go. It is incumbent upon us to sustain the gains under RTL, albeit with critical modifications to strengthen it further and ensure optimum impact in its implementation,” Secretary Tiu Laurel said.\n\n
He said major amendments to the RTL that DA is proposing include:
⁃ strengthening the role of NFA as price stabilizer by restoring its ability to import if needed to boost domestic supply and only through the Authority of the DA Secretary; its warehouse registration and monitoring functions; and its power to regulate rice prices and market supply.\n\n
⁃ allocation of rice import tariff revenues exceeding P15 billion to various programs aimed at financial assistance, crop diversification, water impounding and watershed rehabilitation and development, and solar power irrigation programs.\n\n
⁃ extension of the Rice Fund until 2030, including reallocation of funds toward farm machinery and post harvest facilities, as well as storage and processing; seed development; and training and extension services, with special attention to soil health improvement initiatives and pest and disease management strategies to protect and enhance rice production;\n\n
⁃ creation of the Rice Industry Development-Program Management Office to serve as the Secretariat of the RCEF that will coordinate the Rice Fund’s interventions, monitor and manage a comprehensive database, and ensure activities of RCEF are effectively implemented.\n\n
“I note that the RTL is just one of the progressive efforts undertaken by the government to build productivity and enhance the resiliency of our agriculture sector and the economy in general. It is an imperative given that Philippine agriculture faces both the challenges of the volatilities caused by global conflicts and the difficulties posed by climate change and natural calamities,” he said.\n\n</string>
</resources>